AFGHANISTAN, 1981
阿富汗,    1981
THE SECOND YEAR OF THE RUSSIAN INVASION
蘇聯入侵阿富汗翌年
Spread out.
散開
Move it.
快點
Get your weapon on, Golikov.
快把武器拿出來
Over here.
在這裡
Kaminski.
卡明斯基
T5447, what's your status?
T5447,你的情況如何?
Just mopping up, sir. Almost done.
我們在收拾殘局,快好了
Rejoin the column. All units rejoin.
所有單位集合
I got 'em.
好了
. Did you get the sheep over there? . Let's say there's a couple left.
-有把那邊的羊處理好嗎? -就說還剩幾頭吧
T5447, Roger, six.
T5447,收到,    6
Behind this one building...
在這棟建築物後面...
Sir. Gotta shoot it?
長官,要開槍嗎?
Give me the flamethrower.
把火焰槍給我
- What you got? . There you go, sir.
-那是什麼? -拿去吧,長官
. Over this way. . On my way.
-從這去 -我馬上來
. Golikov, come on. . I'm coming.
-戈利可夫，快來 -我來了
Bring that cyanide canister.
把氰化物拿來
Where's the extra satchels? Bring 'em over here.
其它的包包呢? 拿過來
Molotov.
瓶裝汽油彈
Look out at your sides. There's another at your six.
小心你那邊 在你的六點鐘方向還有
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
I'm burning!
我燒起來了!
Right there.
在那裡
Oh, God.
天啊
I can't put it out.
我滅不掉
. You owe me one. . Get him over here.
-你欠我一個人情 -把他帶過來
Come on, get his arm. Come on.
快,扶他的手
Move it!
快點
You son of a bitch!
你這個龜兒子!
You're dead!
你死定了
Put him under the track.
把他放在車輪下
Put your feet under there.
把腳放在下面
Do you want me to kick him?
要我踢他嗎?
You think you can kill my friends and get away with it?
你以為在殺了我的朋友後 還能全身而退嗎?
Koverchenko, mount and crank it up.
柯夫柴可夫,去發動坦克
We're gonna squash you like a grape.
我們要把你壓扁
Ask him where the other rebels are.
問他其他的反抗軍在哪裡
Where are the rebels?
反抗軍在哪裡?
Mujahedeen are all around you!
反抗軍如影隨形無所不在
Ten Russian dogs will die for every Afghan!
每死一個阿富汗人 就要十個俄國毛子償命
What did he say?
他說什麼?
He does not know, sir.
他不知道,長官
Tell them to stop.
叫他們停
No further!
不要再過來了!
Let him go!
讓他走!
Sherina! I order you away from here!
莎琳娜,我命令妳退後
This commander prefers bullets to words. Go!
這名指揮官嗜殺成性,快走!
Traitor!
叛徒!
Tell your shit eater of a commander to let him go!
叫你的狗屁指揮官放他走!
These women, they humbly beg you for the prisoner, sir.
放了那名囚犯,長官
You tell them to watch what happens to him.
叫她們好好看清楚他的下場
Do it.
動手
He is to be my husband!
他是我丈夫
No Russian will escape Afghanistan!
沒有俄國人能活著離開阿富汗
Forward.
前進
Allah is the only God...!
阿拉是唯一的真主...!
- Direction, sir? - Right fork.
-長官要往哪走? -走右邊那條
- What?
-什麼?
Sir, are you sure?
長官,你確定嗎?
Driver, I said, "Right fork." Do you copy?
我說「右邊」,聽到沒有?
Yes, sir.
是的,長官
T5447, do you copy?
T5447,聽到了沒有?
What's your position?
你的位置在哪裡?
- Why can't they hear us? - Do you copy?
-他們為什麼聽不到? -聽到了沒有?
T5447, do you copy?
T5447,聽到了嗎?
T5447...
T5447...
The tank is lost.
那輛坦克完了
No...
不...
We need help.
我們需要協助
Hasaad!
哈珊!
Taj...
泰伊...
Uncle...
叔叔...
Come on.
跟我來
Uncle... why?
叔叔...為什麼?
Retaliation.
復仇
Be his mother.
好好照顧他
Sherina.
莎琳娜
Moustafa!
穆塔法!
Salaam, Taj Mohamed.
你好,泰伊穆罕默德
Cousin, truce.
我們休戰吧
Greetings, uncle.
你好,叔叔
Salaam, Moustafa.
你好,穆塔法
I always said, have faith in Allah and keep a hidden pistol.
我一直說要信仰阿拉 並做萬全準備
Every part of me screams to see your blood.
我恨不得讓你血濺五步
Nothing has changed between us, then.
那我們完全沒有變啊
Taj, your father would never dishonor a truce.
泰伊,你父親說休戰的話 就不會食言
What do you want here?
你來這裡幹嘛?
One of the tanks that killed your people is lost in the valley of the Jackal.
屠殺你們人民的坦克之一 在胡狼谷裡迷路了
I know that valley.
我知道那座山谷
It only has one way in and out.
山谷只有一處可供進出
I come to call upon your honor to avenge Afghanistan.
我是來請求你發揮榮譽心 為阿富汗報仇的
When Moustafa talks of honor...
當穆塔法講到榮譽...
...the end of the world is at hand.
...表示世界末日就不遠了
Cousin, uncle, we are tired of this ancient vendetta.
表哥,叔叔,我們對這種 世代仇殺已經厭煩了
Let us take revenge together... We divide the booty.
我們一起為國復仇... 所得的利益均分
I will not fight with a scavenger...
我才不要跟像你這樣...
...who picks gold from the teeth of dead Russians.
...會從俄國人屍體上 拔金牙的人合作
Then run to Pakistan.
那你就逃到巴基斯坦去吧
I would speak with the Khan.
我要先去請示首領
My father was killed.
我爸爸被殺了
My brother Shahzaman is now Khan.
我哥哥沙薩曼現在是首領
Your brother was martyred by a Russian tank.
你哥哥被蘇俄坦克壓死了
You are now Khan, Taj Mohamed.
泰伊穆罕默德,現在首領是你
Shahzaman.
沙薩曼
My Khan, we would fight with you to avenge Shahzaman.
首領,我們要為沙薩曼復仇
With this we can destroy the tank!
我們要用這把槍摧毀坦克
I know how to work it!
我知道怎麼用!
What do you say, Taj?
怎麼樣,泰伊?
Your brother did not go to Pakistan... He went to Paradise.
你哥哥不是逃到 巴基斯坦去了...他到天國去了
Allah...
阿拉...
Give me a man to tear apart.
找個人讓我洩心頭之恨吧
From this time forth...
從現在開始...
...I am a stone in your sling!
...我是您彈弓裡的石頭!
Revenge!
復仇!
Sir, I can't seem to raise them.
長官,我聯絡不到他們
Scared as shit!
瞧你嚇的!
Come on!
快點!
Got any of that splash on you?
你身上有沒有酒?
Sir.
長官
Where the hell are we?
我們在哪裡?
I don't know, sir.
不知道
How do we get to Kandahar Road?
我們要怎麼才能到堪達哈路?
I'm not sure, sir.
我不知道,長官
The Molotov took our radio out.
我們的無線電被炸彈毀了
We get reception but no transmission, sir.
現在只能收訊不能發話
Those hills must be here.
那些山頭一定是在這裡
Kandahar Road is on the other side of those hills?
對吧?
I'm not sure. The grid coordinates are 31 degrees latitude...
現在座標是緯度31度--
Samad, you're relieved of your post.
沙曼,這件事你不用管了
Give the log to Koverchenko.
把日誌交給柯夫柴可夫
. For what reason? . Incompetence. Record it.
-為什麼呢長官 -因為你無能
. What is my function? . None.
-那我現在的任務是什麼? -你什麼都不用做
Give yourself a battlefield commendation.
你得到戰地勳章
. For what, sir? . For trying to save those tankers.
-因為你試圖搶救同袍
To your post!
就定位!
Just say, "Yes, sir," and keep out of his way.
別礙他的事就好
Okay.
好
Why did that rebel we ran over laugh at me?
我們壓死的叛軍為什麼笑我?
He wasn't laughing at you, he was happy.
他不是在笑你,他是高興
Such men believe if they die in a Holy War, they will go to Paradise.
他們認為要是為聖戰而死 就可以到天國去
Do you believe that?
你相信嗎?
After university, I'm not sure what I believe.
我也不清楚自己究竟相信什麼
I need a woman!
我需要女人!
Maybe you'll find another sheep.
也許你能找到一頭羊
Maybe I will.
也許吧
Kaminski, turn that music off.
卡明斯基,把音樂關掉
Golikov put it on, sir.
是戈利可夫開的
Kaminski, you shit!
卡明斯基,你這個小人!
Come here for a second. I've got something to show you.
過來,我有東西給你看
Crank it up!
發動坦克!
Gunner.
砲手
Troops on the ridge!
山上有敵軍!
Turret power.
砲塔注意
Range.
射程
Three. Zero. Zero.
3—0—0
At my command.
聽我的口令
What's around?
附近有什麼?
Get it out of here.
快走
Ready to roll.
我們可以出發了
Driver. Forward. Go!
駕駛,前進,快點!
Frag!
手榴彈!
Heads up, Samad.
小心,沙曼
Traversing.
旋轉砲口
Up.
向上
Fire.
開火
On the way.
馬上好
Let's go!
咱們走!
Moustafa.
穆塔法
You said you could kill the tank in one shot!
你說一槍就能解決那輛坦克
Maybe it is not the will of Allah.
也許阿拉另有打算
Or maybe you are a bad shot!
也許是你槍法不好!
I am Khan!
我是首領!
I demand to be the one to explode the tank!
我要自己解決那輛坦克!
Give me the RPG!
把火箭砲給我!
Your nephew is a hothead, uncle.
你姪子性子真火爆
Moustafa.
穆塔法
We all stay together!
我們不能分散!
Taj.
泰伊
Who calls himself Khan is not a Khan.
自稱是首領的不配當首領
Patience, Taj.
你要有耐心,泰伊
This is your trial.
這是你的試煉
Uncle?
叔叔?
It's nothing. A scratch.
沒什麼,皮肉傷罷了
Come...
來...
Allah gives us tracks to follow.
阿拉已經指點我們一條明路
Khanzaman! Afzal! Come on!
坎薩曼!阿薩爾!跟我來!
Only one drank the water, goddamnit. Samad!
可惡,沙曼! 只有一個人喝而已
I told you to throw the canister far away.
我不是叫你把罐子丟遠點嗎?
They found it.
被他們找到了
At my command, gunner. Frag.
聽我的口令,砲手,手榴彈
Move.
快點
Frag is up.
準備好了
. Fire. . On the way.
-開火. -馬上好
Misfire.
不成功
Go to manual.
改由手控
Out of the tank!
全部出來!
. What happened? . Misfire.
-怎麼了? -發射不成
I know it's gonna blow.
坦克車就要爆炸了
The shell looked okay to me.
我剛剛看過砲彈沒問題
. Samad. . Yes, sir?
-什麼事,長官?
Did you touch that shell?
你是不是碰過砲彈?
Yes, sir.
是的,長官
I just handed it... I handed it to Golikov, sir.
我把它交給戈利可夫
That's all.
就這樣
Misfires happen, sir. One in every 100 rounds.
開火不成功的機率是百分之一
Cook. Off.
槍管太熱
It's the loader's responsibility to unload.
拆彈是裝彈手的責任
Golikov.
戈利可夫
Sir, I've never handled a cook. Off before.
長官,我從沒處理過這種情況
I will do it, sir.
我去,長官
He doesn't know what he's doing. Let me go in there.
讓我去吧
All right.
好
. Kaminski. . Sir?
-長官?
Pinpoint the Mujas.
瞄準反抗軍
. Don't take your eyes off them. . Yes, sir.
-別讓他們離開你的視線 -遵命,長官
Koverchenko. Golikov.
柯夫柴可夫,戈利可夫
Come on.
快點
Sir, maybe I ought to do this.
長官,最好讓我來做
What if something happens?
萬一出事怎麼辦?
Then Kaminski will have his first command.
那就輪到卡明斯基發號施令
Just tell me one thing, Koverchenko.
告訴我,柯夫柴可夫
Why do you stick up for the Afghan?
你為什麼要幫那個阿富汗人?
Because he's doing his best, sir.
因為他盡力了
That's what worries me.
我擔心的就是這點
You've got what it takes. I've seen it.
你天生有領導人的才能
Keep your head on straight.
你千萬別被沖昏頭了
Why don't we turn and fight the rebels?
我們乾脆去修理那些叛軍
'Cause they could put a fucking hole right through us with that RPG.
打得我們落花流水
Come on, go.
咱們走
Come on.
快點
. What the hell happened? . They're gone, sir.
-怎麼了? -他們不見了,長官
Lucky bastards don't know Samad saved their lives.
沙曼幫他們撿回一條狗命
I didn't do anything.
我什麼都沒做
Booby trap that round.
你去埋詭雷
Come on.
跟我來
Driver, crank it up.
駕駛,發動
Careful.
小心
Get us out of here.
快離開這裡
Moving tank.
發動坦克
We bleed because we are weak for Russian junk.
我們會受傷是因為 垂涎蘇俄人的垃圾
Your mujahed has no chance to live.
你的人活不了了
Our uncle is wounded too. Let him stay here with Noor.
我們的叔叔也受傷了 讓他留下來陪諾爾
My wound will heal when I see the tank explode.
只要親眼看到坦克爆炸 我就會不藥而癒
We leave him food and water.
留點食物跟水給他
God is great.
天神是萬能的
Another grave.
又一座墳墓
The wind covers the tank tracks... we want to return to the village.
風會吹散坦克的痕跡... 我們要回村子去了
You have no village ... only "Badal"!
你們不該想家只能想復仇
A Holy Man.
一個聖人
David! You have come!
大衛!你來了!
Prophet Mohamed bid me build a fire to light your way.
先知穆罕默德要我生火 為你們照路
God willing, with only a stone you will slay The Beast, David!
有了天神的幫助 你們用石頭擊敗怪獸!
What Beast?
什麼怪獸?
Goliath!
歌利亞!
Look Taj... tank tracks!
看,泰伊...是坦克的痕跡!
Build a fire, sir?
要生火嗎,長官?
I'm sure you lost those Muja. Fucks, sir.
我們一定已一擺脫叛軍了
Tend to the track, Kaminski.
卡明斯基,去修輪子
You got it, sir.
沒問題,長官
Oh, God.
天啊
Let me hit that thing.
我來敲一下
It is called Pakhtunali. It's the code of honor.
它叫巴突納里 是榮譽宣言
Three obligations.
一共有三大原則
First, "Milmastia," hospitality.
第一是要好客
Second, "Badal," revenge.
第二是要復仇
Third, "Nanawatai."
第三叫做「納納瓦泰」
The obligation to give sanctuary to all those who ask.
就是對有需要的人伸出援手
. To all? . AII.
-對所有人? -是的
. Even the enemy?
-包括敵人?
What if I kill your brother...
萬一我殺了你的兄弟...
...and you come for Badal, revenge?
...你來找我尋仇
And I ask for Nanawatai?
我卻要求你保護我怎麼辦?
Then I would be obligated to feed, clothe and protect you.
給你穿,保護你
That's incredibly civilized.
真文明啊
What is it, Nanawatai?
納納瓦泰是什麼?
Bread?
麵包?
Smells like he's been chewing on fucking buffalo shit.
他嘴巴臭死了
When we get back, you gotta transfer out of this tank.
我們回去後你想辦法調走吧
I'll win his respect in time.
我遲早會贏得他的敬重
Listen to me.
你聽我說
When he gets on your back there's no way to shake him.
他很固執 想要改變他的看法是不可能的
My dear Konstantin.
親愛的朋友
I regard this abuse as the price I must pay to learn.
我認為這是學習的代價
I love Afghanistan, but we are a flea in the tail of a bear.
我很愛阿富汗 但我們這是螳臂擋車
We must join the 20th century.
我們一定要進入20世紀
And when Afghans accept that, I will be there.
我就會為阿富汗效力
Knowing technology and Russian.
我很了解科技和俄國人
. So, you're a patriot? . Yes.
-你很愛國? -是的
So was that rebel.
那個叛黨也很愛國
He wanted to keep things the way they've always been.
他拒絕改變
I wish I believed in something that much.
我真希望能像你這麼有信心
I envy him.
我羨慕他
Then why did you crush him?
那你為什麼要壓死他?
Because I had no choice.
因為我別無選擇
. You always have a choice. . Give it.
-總是有選擇的 -拿來
You never told me she sent nudes of herself.
你沒告訴我她寄裸照來
Give it to me.
拿來
She's got that nympho look.
她看起來像花痴
I got the half I want.
我拿到我想要的那一半
You son of a bitch.
你這個龜兒子
Get the fuck off me.
放開我
. What the hell is going on? . Nothing, sir.
-在幹什麼? -沒事,長官
Thanks, Konstantin.
謝了,康士坦丁
What is this?
這是什麼?
Brake fluid!
煞車油!
No wonder they don't work.
難怪煞車不管用
It keeps me steady on the gun, sir.
這樣我操縱砲台時才不會發抖
I filter it through bread, and get out all the shit.
我用麵包濾出毒素
Then I put in raisins and sugar, I put it out in the sun.
加入葡萄乾和糖放在太陽下曬
It ferments in a few days. Gets a pretty good kick.
發酵幾天後就變成烈酒
Write him up, sir?
長官,要記警告嗎?
Get over here.
過來
For one mistake?
為了這點小事?
He's the best gunner in the division.
他是我手下最好的砲手
Omit it.
劃掉
It's already done, sir. In ink.
我已經白紙黑字寫下來了
You'd better watch your ass from now on.
你最好給我小心點
Sometimes Afghan snipers pick off tank drivers.
有時候阿富汗狙擊手 專挑坦克駕駛下手
Sometimes tank drivers pick 'em off first.
有時我們能先下手為強
Grenade!
手榴彈!
Get down!
趴下!
Shit.
可惡
Don't blow it up!
不要炸!
Kill the Russians underneath, not the tank!
殺下面的俄國人不要炸坦克!
Grenade!
手榴彈!
Open the hatch.
快把坦克打開
We're getting slaughtered down here.
我們躲在下面只有死路一條
I'm bleeding.
我在流血
Inside.
快進來
Get inside.
快進去
Get in the tank. Hurry up!
快進坦克!
Koverchenko, get us the hell outta here.
柯夫柴可夫,快離開這兒
Hurry up!
快點!
We've got a fire on top.
車頂著火了
. I'm dying! . I can't see.
-我要死了! -我看不到
I'm dying!
我要死了!
Hard right!
右轉!
Gunner, traverse right, 180.
砲手,向右180度
I'm dying!
我要死了!
Traversing.
快轉砲台
I can't see through the fire, sir!
前方有火焰,我看不到!
Gunner, identify.
砲手,認清目標
Bead on the fire of our campsite!
瞄準我們剛剛生的那堆火!
I can't get elevation.
不夠高
We can detect anything in 100 meter radius.
我們可以偵測 方圓一百公尺內的動靜
They must have camels. That's got to be how they're keeping up.
他們一定有駱駝 不然絕對追不上我們
I can't believe how bad they want this tank.
我真不敢相信 他們真的這麼想要這輛坦克
. They just keep coming. . Shut up.
-人越來越多 -閉嘴
How much longer do we stay here?
我們還要在這裡留多久?
Till first light when we can see where we're going.
明天天一亮我們就走
Crack the hatch, sir?
要不要我打開坦克蓋?
No.
不要
Sir, I have to piss.
長官,我要解手
Hold it.
忍著點
Do we have any water, Samad?
有水嗎,沙曼?
All the canteens were left behind. All the rations, too.
水和食物都丟在營地
Great.
這下好了
Your pals will feast tonight.
你的同胞有的吃了
We don't need food and water. We're safe in here.
我們不需要食物和水 我們在這裡很安全
My tanks have been hit by everything.
我的坦克身經百戰
In Mongolia once...
在蒙古...
RPG. Direct hit.
被火箭砲直接命中
Commander, gunner and turret went flying.
指揮官,砲手和砲塔全完了
I drove the rest of the tank back to our lines.
但我還是把坦克開了回去
These tanks today are better.
今天的坦克比以前的好多了
Much better.
好太多了
I don't think I can hold it much longer.
我快憋不住了
Sir!
長官!
. How many? .20, 25.
-多少人? -20,    25個
They're all around us.
我們已經被包圍了
Battle stations!
就作戰位置!
Wait. I don't think they see us, the way they're moving.
等等,別讓他們看到我們
They're in effective RPG range.
他們已經進入射程範圍
Gunner, troops, frag.
砲手,弟兄們,準備開砲
Frag is up, sir.
準備好了
Identify.
確認目標
I can't identify, it's too dark.
沒辦法,太暗了
Go to IR.
用紅外線
IR is busted.
紅外線壞了
They're all around us, sir.
他們已經包圍我們了
Stand by to traverse left, 360.
向左360度
All weapons fire at my command.
聽我的口令開火
Traverse. Fire!
轉砲台,開火!
Up.
上去
Cease fire!
停火!
All dead, sir.
都死了,長官
Samad.
沙曼
Go verify.
你去看看
. Move it. . Yes, sir.
-快 -是的,長官
Kaminski, stand down.
卡明斯基,下來
Koverchenko, get on the co. Ax.
柯夫柴可夫,你負責機關鎗
Set Samad in your sights.
瞄準沙曼
What?
什麼?
Take him now, he's a traitor.
殺了他,他是叛徒
Are you insane?
你瘋啦?
Your insubordination has gotten you demoted from Intelligence...
你不守命令 才會從情報單位降職...
...to Rescue Operations, to this tank. Your next stop is prison.
到拯救和坦克單位 你下一站就是監獄
With a record like that, I wouldn't disobey another order.
你素行不良,最好不要再抗命
Take Samad, now.
快殺了沙曼
No.
不
How many dead?
死了多少人?
It's deer, sir.
是鹿,長官
It's a herd of deer.
是一群鹿
The Russian kills just to kill.
俄國人為殺鹿而殺鹿
We're leaking oil, sir.
我們在漏油,長官
. Raise the snorkel and seal the cannon. . Are we going under water?
-升起通氣管封住砲口 -我們要下水嗎?
There are rebels behind us and they're following our tracks.
後面有反抗軍追縱我們
Samad, stop it.
沙曼,別鬧了
I'm in my prayers, sir.
我在祈禱,長官
Get up.
起來
Sir.
長官
If I'm able to reconcile dialectical materialism and Allah...
如果我能綜合唯物論和阿拉...
...isn't that my business?
...我要祈禱難道不可以嗎?
Why do you not trust me, sir?
你為什麼不信任我?
You know I'm a member of the Party.
你知道我是共產黨員
My son is in the cultural exchange in Moscow.
我兒子在莫斯科求學
Do you think I would compromise my son?
你認為我會危及我兒子嗎?
I said, "Get up."
我叫你起來
See how deep the river is.
去看看這條河有多深
How, sir?
怎麼看?
Walk in it.
走進去
You don't need that.
你不需要那個
Like ice, sir.
水很冰
I didn't ask for the temperature.
我又沒有問你水的溫度
Is the bottom mud or stone?
河底是泥濘還是石頭?
Stone.
石頭
No!
不!
Why?
為什麼?
. I said, "Why?" . Shut up!
-閉嘴!
What are you doing?
你在做什麼?
Recording, sir.
我在記錄,長官
Write yourself up. This time your insubordination's got you a court. Martial.
連你一塊兒記上去吧 這次我要你接受軍法審判
So will killing your own men, sir!
殺自己人也要接受軍法審判!
If you were commander, you would've done the same thing.
如果你是指揮官也會這麼做的
Samad was waiting for his chance to deliver this tank to the enemy.
把這輛坦克交給敵人
But I was too smart for him.
但是我沒有上他的當
And I didn't study philosophy.
我沒有唸過哲學
I read your dossier, Mr. Intellectual.
我看過你的檔案,知識份子
What would you say your record says about you?
你想知道上級對你的評語嗎?
That I think for myself.
我有獨立思考的能力
You think for yourself.
你能獨立思考
When I was eight years old defending Stalingrad, I didn't think for myself.
我別無選擇
When the Motherland asked for our lives, we gave.
祖國要我們獻出生命 我們就照做
My father didn't think of himself, he gave.
我爸爸想都不想就奉獻
My mother didn't think of herself, she gave.
我媽媽想都不想就奉獻
My brother didn't think of himself, he gave.
我哥哥想都不想就奉獻
My comrades tied a rope around my waist and lowered me on top of Nazi tanks.
我的同志們用跟繩索 把我放到納綷坦克上
I stuffed Molotovs under turret and cannon.
我把燃燒彈塞砲台和大砲
And they pulled me up again. Eight years old.
我當時才八歲
They called me Tank Boy.
他們叫我坦克小子
I took a lot of Nazi tanks.
我解決了不少納綷坦克
A lot.
真的不少
Over the years, I've learned to smell a traitor.
經過多年歷練 我一眼就知道誰是叛徒
. How bad is it? . You mean the tank?
-你是說坦克嗎?
Konstantin, do you think he's snapped?
康士丁,你說他是不是瘋了?
. What are you doing? . What?
-幹嘛? -什麼?
You wanna be next? Don't be seen talking to this asshole.
你要自找苦吃? 別讓他看見你和這小子說話
How much further can we go?
我們還能走多遠?
Not far enough.
不夠遠
We should just ditch this bitch...
我們應該放棄這輛坦克...
...dismantle the dosh gun, fucking walk to Kandahar Road.
...把武器拆下來 一路走到堪達哈路
What are you whispering about?
你們在說什麼?
Kaminski had an interesting idea, sir.
卡明斯基有個點子
Ditching the tank and walking back.
放棄坦克走回去
He's a fucking liar, sir!
長官,他說謊!
As a man who thinks for himself, Koverchenko, what do you think?
你是個有主見的人 你對這有何看法?
Well, sir, the road wheel's cracked.
長官,我們的輪子不能用了
Kaminski drank our brakes. We're low on petrol.
卡明斯基把煞車油喝了 我們汽油不夠
The battery's low, we're losing oil.
電池快沒電了,還在漏油
If the engine heats up, it'll seize.
引擎如果過熱的話就完了
Terrain, obviously against us. We have no rations.
地勢崎嶇,我們沒有糧食
The Mujas don't seem to need rations, petrol or anything we know of and...
反抗軍無需糧食、汽油...
...they have an RPG.
...他們有火箭筒
Their aim is getting better, sir.
而且準頭越來越好
You admire them, don't you?
你很佩服他們,對吧?
They've got us on the run, don't they?
他們追的我們四處逃竄,對吧
What do you suggest? Surrender?
難不成要我們投降?
Clearly, that's a direct violation of Soviet military law.
這直接違反蘇聯軍法
But you're all for it, aren't you?
但是你卻舉雙手讚成?
That's mutiny, Koverchenko.
這是叛變,柯夫柴可夫
Try it.
你有種試試看
Kaminski, get his weapon. Cover him.
卡明斯基,去拿他的槍瞄準他
Yes, sir.
是的,長官
Golikov, get some rope.
戈利可夫,去拿繩子
Now!
現在去!
Tie him to that rock.
把他綁在石頭上
I'll haunt you, Kaminski. I'll be your worst nightmare.
卡明斯基,我不會放過你的
Shut up.
閉嘴
You hear me?
聽到了嗎?
. Be an idiot. . I don't believe this.
-我不相信
Hold still, asshole.
不要動,渾球
. What are we doing? . You shut up!
-我們在幹嘛? -你閉嘴!
He fucking stepped in this one himself.
他是自作自受
You're a fucking lackey!
你真沒用!
Fuck.
幹
. Get the log book. . Yes, sir.
-拿紀錄簿來 -是的,長官
He doesn't have it, sir. He must've left it in the tank.
不在這裡,長官 他一定是放在坦克上
Booby trap him.
在他身下裝詭雷
Twisted, insane. Don't be an idiot.
真變態,你別傻了
Don't move.
不要動
If you need anything...
有什麼需要的話...
...just nod.
...就點頭吧
Konstantin, I'm sorry.
康士丁,對不對
Anton, you're next.
安東,下一個就是你
Go to the tank, blow his brains out, come back and untie me.
你去殺了他,回來替我鬆綁
. You're next. . I can't.
-輪到你了 -我不能
You hear me?
聽到了嗎?
Anton, don't leave me here. Don't leave.
安東,別把我留在這裡
. I can't. . Untie me.
-替我鬆綁
You're a good soldier.
你是個好軍人
You can be counted on when they ask you to shoot your mother.
他們要你射殺自己母親時 你也會照做
Golikov! Goddamnit.
戈利可夫!該死的
Don't leave me here, you coward.
不要丟下我,懦夫
Golikov, you fuck.
戈利可夫,你這個渾球
I think you did the right thing, sir.
長官,你做的很對
I appreciate that, Kaminski.
多謝誇獎,卡明斯基
I think I speak for all of us when I say that.
我這話是代表大家說的
What he wrote in here could close doors for the rest of your lives.
他寫的這些東西 會害人永世不得翻身
I don't know why you didn't just kill him, sir.
不乾脆殺了他?
I was trying to buy us some time.
我要為我們爭取時間
The tank's roomier now.
坦克裡寬敞多了
Sherina!
莎琳娜!
What are you doing here?
妳在這裡做什麼?